<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis and Insights on FALSE FIRE</title>
    <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis and Insights on FALSE FIRE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration and Refugee Board of Canada: China: Situation of Falun Gong practitioners and treatment by state authorities (2001-2005)</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/situation_of_falun_gong_practitioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/situation_of_falun_gong_practitioners/</guid>
      <description>China: Situation of Falun Gong practitioners and treatment by state authorities (2001-2005) (Excerpts 1) By Immigration and Refugee Board of Canada
October 31, 2005
[&amp;hellip;]
Situation of Falun Gong Practitioners and Government Response since 2000
A government campaign against Falun Gong practitioners (Chang 2004, 18; International Religious Freedom Report 2001 26 Oct. 2001, Sec. 2), purportedly with the aim of sending all remaining adherents into custody and forcing them to renounce the movement, unfolded in the aftermath of 23 January 2001 (ibid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FalunInfo.net: Investigation Uncovers More Lies in Chinese Regime’s Story of Tragic Self-Immolation Incident</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/investigation_uncovers_more_lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2003 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/investigation_uncovers_more_lies/</guid>
      <description>Investigation Uncovers More Lies in Chinese Regime‘s Story of Tragic Self-Immolation Incident By FalunInfo.net
May 23, 2003
WASHINGTON DC (FDI) – Mr. John Jaw, the president of an organization investigating atrocities against Falun Gong practitioners in China, has a fantastic story to tell.
Former Chinese leader, Jiang Zemin, ordered underlings to assemble a group of individuals who would light themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square. The incident would be framed as a dramatic suicide and pegged on Falun Gong – all with the intent to marshal public opinion against the spiritual practice that Jiang had tried so desperately to crush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FalunInfo.net: The Tiananmen Square &#34;Self-Immolation&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/the_tiananmen_square_self_immolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2003 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/the_tiananmen_square_self_immolation/</guid>
      <description>The Tiananmen Square &amp;ldquo;Self-Immolation&amp;rdquo; Potent Hate Propaganda Turns the Tide against Falun Gong in China
By FalunInfo.net
December 14, 2001
On January 23, 2001, five individuals allegedly set themselves on fire in Tienanmen Square. Within hours, Chinese authorities flooded the state-run media with grisly photos of the event, claiming the self-immolators were Falun Gong practitioners. Days later, a Washington Post article revealed that at least two of the self-immolators had never been seen practicing Falun Gong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporters without Borders: The International Press Still Prevented from Covering the Activities of the Falungong Movement</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/international_press_prevented_from_covering_falun_gong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/international_press_prevented_from_covering_falun_gong/</guid>
      <description>Reporters without Borders: The international press still prevented from covering the activities of the Falungong movement (Cached copy 1) Three journalists detained on Tiananmen Square
By Reporters without Borders December 4, 2001
On 20 November 2001, Jutta Lietsch, correspondent of the German newspaper Leipziger Volkszeitung and contributor to the daily Tageszeitung, Wen-Chun Fan, cameraman of the American TV channel CNN, Stefan Niemann, correspondent of the German TV channel ARD in Beijing and her assistant were detained and questioned by the police while they were covering the demonstration of 35 Western followers of the spiritual movement Falungong on Tiananmen Square in Beijing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danny Schechter, Washington Post: The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing?</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</guid>
      <description>The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing? (Cached copy1) By Danny Schechter
February 22, 2001
What could be more dramatic? People are setting themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square in the heart of Beijing. CNN is there. The police just happen to have fire extinguishers on hand, and the victims are rushed to a hospital after their agonies are thoroughly photographed for state television. While the government-controlled media uncharacteristically releases the story at once, it takes a week of production before video footage is aired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Noonan: Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/beijing_is_burning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/beijing_is_burning/</guid>
      <description>Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC (Cached copy1) Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong
By Ann Noonan, Policy Director for the Laogai Foundation
February 13, 2001
Caught up in its desperate bid to host the 2008 Olympic Games, Beijing is a city in turmoil. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s insistence on soi-disant &amp;ldquo;social and political stability&amp;rdquo; has allowed it to resort to old Communist tactics reminiscent of Chairman Mao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philip Pan, Washington Post: Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery</title>
      <link>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.falsefire.com/en/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</guid>
      <description>Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery (Excerpts 1) Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong
By Philip P. Pan February 4, 2001
KAIFENG, China (Washington Post Foreign Service) — There is a neighborhood on the eastern side of this once-glorious city called Apple Orchard, but there are no apple trees here, only drab concrete buildings and clusters of unemployed men loitering on mud streets. It was here, in a fourth-floor apartment in Building Six, that Liu Chunling and her 12-year-old daughter, Liu Siying, lived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>