<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis and Insights on FALSE FIRE</title>
    <link>/en/reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis and Insights on FALSE FIRE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Danny Schechter, Washington Post: The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing?</title>
      <link>/en/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</guid>
      <description>The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing? By Danny Schechter
February 22, 2001
What could be more dramatic? People are setting themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square in the heart of Beijing. CNN is there. The police just happen to have fire extinguishers on hand, and the victims are rushed to a hospital after their agonies are thoroughly photographed for state television. While the government-controlled media uncharacteristically releases the story at once, it takes a week of production before video footage is aired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Noonan: Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC</title>
      <link>/en/reports/beijing_is_burning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/reports/beijing_is_burning/</guid>
      <description>Web Archive
Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong (Excerpts [^1])
By Ann Noonan, Policy Director for the Laogai Foundation
February 13, 2001
Caught up in its desperate bid to host the 2008 Olympic Games, Beijing is a city in turmoil. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s insistence on soi-disant &amp;ldquo;social and political stability&amp;rdquo; has allowed it to resort to old Communist tactics reminiscent of Chairman Mao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philip Pan, Washington Post: Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery</title>
      <link>/en/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</guid>
      <description>Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong (Excerpts 1)
By Philip P. Pan
February 4, 2001
KAIFENG, China (Washington Post Foreign Service) — There is a neighborhood on the eastern side of this once-glorious city called Apple Orchard, but there are no apple trees here, only drab concrete buildings and clusters of unemployed men loitering on mud streets. It was here, in a fourth-floor apartment in Building Six, that Liu Chunling and her 12-year-old daughter, Liu Siying, lived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>