<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>False Fire Homepage on False Fire (F)</title>
    <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in False Fire Homepage on False Fire (F)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>À propos du programme vidéo False Fire</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/about/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;à-propos-du-programme-vidéo-false-fire&#34;&gt;À propos du programme vidéo False Fire&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La vidéo False Fire: China&amp;rsquo;s Tragic New Standard in State Deception qui analyse l&amp;rsquo;incident &amp;ldquo;auto-immolation&amp;rdquo; de 2001 sur la place Tiananmen Square, a obtenu la mention Certificate of Honorable Mention lors du 51ème Columbus International Film &amp;amp; Video Festival. New Tang Dynasty TV, qui est une chaîne de télévision chinoise privée à but non lucratif, a produit le film. La cérémonie de remise du prix s&amp;rsquo;est tenu au the Kansas Center, Columbus Arts College, Columbus, dans l&amp;rsquo;Etat de l&amp;rsquo;Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dans le programme vidéo False Fire, NTD TV, dont le but est de fournir une information non biaisée et authentique et de soutenir les droits de l&amp;rsquo;Homme, celle-ci a mené des investigations aux endroits suspects de l&amp;rsquo;incident. Le résultat de l&amp;rsquo;analyse a révélé que la soit disant affaire d&amp;rsquo;auto-immolation a fort probalement été orchestrée par le gouvernement chinois afin de contenir le mouvement du Falun Gong et de fabriquer des excuses pour persécuter le Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration and Refugee Board of Canada: China: Situation of Falun Gong practitioners and treatment by state authorities (2001-2005)</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/situation_of_falun_gong_practitioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/situation_of_falun_gong_practitioners/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;china-situation-of-falun-gong-practitioners-and-treatment-by-state-authorities-2001-2005-excerpts-1&#34;&gt;China: Situation of Falun Gong practitioners and treatment by state authorities (2001-2005) (Excerpts &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Immigration and Refugee Board of Canada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;October 31, 2005&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Situation of Falun Gong Practitioners and Government Response since 2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A government campaign against Falun Gong practitioners (Chang 2004, 18; International Religious Freedom Report 2001 26 Oct. 2001, Sec. 2), purportedly with the aim of sending all remaining adherents into custody and forcing them to renounce the movement, unfolded in the aftermath of 23 January 2001 (ibid.). On that day, a group of alleged Falun Gong practitioners set themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square (AFP 31 Jan. 2001; Asia Times Online 10 Apr. 2002; Chang 2004, 16). However, Falun Gong spokespersons denied that the people involved in the immolations were practitioners (ibid; AFP 31 Jan. 2001; Chang 2004, 18; CNN 24 Jan. 2001), and argued instead that the government had staged the incident (AFP 11 July 2002; NTD TV 2001).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2001, following a high-level meeting of the Communist Party Central Committee, then-President Jiang Zemin reportedly instructed local and provincial authorities to &amp;ldquo;strengthen local control over Falungong practitioners&amp;rdquo; (HRW Jan. 2002, 35). Practitioners who actively engaged in Falun Gong were ordered detained, and all sectors of society were to play their part in ensuring that Falun Gong practitioners recanted their beliefs (ibid., 36; see also Chang 2004, 18-19; International Religious Freedom Report 2001 26 Oct. 2001, Sec. 2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two subsequent self-immolations were reported (Chang 2004, 17, 21). Maria Hsia Chang wrote in The End of Days that one self-immolation occurred on 16 February 2001 in a residential neighbourhood of Beijing (Chang 2004, 17). Another self-immolation was reported on 1 July 2001 by Xinhua News Agency, which maintained that a 19 year-old adherent of Falun Gong had set himself on fire in an attempt to rid himself of evil and reach a &amp;ldquo;higher level&amp;rdquo; of the practice (ibid., 21).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While practitioners reportedly held frequent demonstrations in Hong Kong, where Falun Gong remained legal (AP 21 Jan. 2004), in Beijing, daily, &amp;ldquo;small-scale&amp;rdquo; protests by practitioners, which had been taking place since the 1999 ban, came to an end following the January 2001 self-immolations incident (AFP 11 July 2002; HRW Jan. 2002, 36). By December 2001, HRW reported, the Chinese government had &amp;ldquo;completely shut down public practice and demonstrations&amp;rdquo; by practitioners (Jan. 2002, 43). Indeed, as a result of the risks for those involved, public demonstrations have become rare (Mosher 22 June 2005; Rachlin 23 June 2005).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Transformation&amp;rdquo; Centres&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2001, following the self-immolations, the 610 Office issued a country-wide order to neighbourhood committees, government institutions and companies to send Falun Gong practitioners to intensive study sessions in order to induce them to renounce their beliefs (China Rights Forum Fall 2001; US June 2004, 11). So-called &amp;ldquo;transformation&amp;rdquo; centres, which fall outside the reach of the judiciary, were set up at the provincial level to compel practitioners to abandon Falun Gong (HRW Jan. 2002, 58). The International Religious Freedom Report 2001 claimed that authorities made local officials, family members and employers responsible for preventing known practitioners from engaging in Falun Gong-related activities (26 Oct. 2001, Sec. 2); schools and employers were required to monitor Falun Gong practitioners and have them sign a statement of renouncement (Rachlin 2 Dec. 2003). If the practitioners refused, they were to be turned in to the local police (ibid.). Grace Wollensak, a representative of the Falun Dafa Association of Canada (FDAC), commented that because employers were not allowed to have Falun Gong practitioners among their workforce, many were compelled to fire practitioners or send them to &amp;ldquo;transformation&amp;rdquo; centres (29 June 2005a). According to the representatives of both HRIC and FDI, by 2005 these policies had not changed (Mosher 22 June 2005; Rachlin 23 June 2005), though their implementation had become &amp;ldquo;more secretive&amp;rdquo; (ibid.). Wollensak commented that &amp;ldquo;there are many cases [of] practitioners [having] lost their jobs&amp;rdquo; but she did not provide any examples (29 June 2005a). The US Department of State reported in June 2004 that &amp;ldquo;[t]housands of individuals may still be undergoing criminal, administrative, and extra-judicial punishment for engaging in Falun Gong practices, admitting adherence to it, or simply refusing to condemn it&amp;rdquo; (US June 2004, 12).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.refworld.org/docid/4b20f02623.html&#34;&gt;RefWorld Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The above are excerpts from the original article published &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.refworld.org/docid/4b20f02623.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FalunInfo.net: Investigation Uncovers More Lies in Chinese Regime’s Story of Tragic Self-Immolation Incident</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/investigation_uncovers_more_lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2003 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/investigation_uncovers_more_lies/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigation-uncovers-more-lies-in-chinese-regime-s-story-of-tragic-self-immolation-incident&#34;&gt;Investigation Uncovers More Lies in Chinese Regime‘s Story of Tragic Self-Immolation Incident&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;FalunInfo.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;May 23, 2003&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON DC (FDI) – Mr. John Jaw, the president of an organization investigating atrocities against Falun Gong practitioners in China, has a fantastic story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Chinese leader, Jiang Zemin, ordered underlings to assemble a group of individuals who would light themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square. The incident would be framed as a dramatic suicide and pegged on Falun Gong – all with the intent to marshal public opinion against the spiritual practice that Jiang had tried so desperately to crush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, says Mr. Jaw, the story is all too real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 23, 2001, five individuals reportedly lit themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square. The Chinese state-run media claimed the individuals were Falun Gong practitioners and assembled a barrage of programs in what the Washington Post
called, “the latest salvo in the [Chinese] government’s escalating campaign to discredit Falun Gong…and win support for its 18-month [now nearly four-year] effort to crush it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critics of the Chinese regime’s persecution of Falun Gong, however, say the entire self-immolation incident was very suspicious. In July 2001, an investigative video was released on the Internet that dissects CCTV footage and references information reported by CNN and the Washington Post to demonstrate that the incident was staged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After viewing the video in a presentation to the Sub-Commission on the Promotion and Protection of Human Rights at the United Nations, the International Education Development (IED) organization said the video “in our view proves that this event was staged by the [Chinese] government.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jaw agrees and three months ago his organization, the World Organization to Investigate the Persecution of Falun Gong (WOIPFG) began its own investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you look at the pieces of this puzzle,” says Mr. Jaw, “the protective clothing worn by the self-immolators, the fire extinguishers and video cameras that were immediately on-hand, the glaring loopholes in subsequent CCTV coverage of the incident…there’s really only one conclusion: The police on Tiananmen Square that day knew what was going to happen. They were ready and had a camera man on-hand to film the whole thing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jaw concludes, “Sadly, the SARS cover-up is just the tip of the iceberg in terms of what this regime is hiding, but with this latest information we have, it’s clear to me that this entire production can’t hold up much longer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “latest information” Mr. Jaw refers to, and that was presented at the press conference in Washington DC, includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two Wang Jindongs Identified: Speech identification technology at a world-renowned laboratory in Chinese speech identification, synthesis and verification determined that the “lead” self-immolator, “Wang Jindong,” who appeared several times on China’s state-run CCTV programs, is actually played by two different people. This evidence supports previous analysis of the hairline and ears of the “Wang Jindong” in the self-immolation footage as being different from the photo of “Wang Jindong” released by China’s state-run media.
Two Critical Hours Gone Missing: Medical personnel at Jishuitan Hospital – the hospital where the self-immolators were rushed to after the incident – revealed that the ambulance carrying the self-immolators arrived two hours after they were loaded into the ambulance on Tiananmen Square. It is only about 6 miles between Tiananmen Square and Jishuitan Hospital. The trip should take approximately 15 minutes. Where were the victims during these two hours?
Mysterious Death of Young Girl: Medical staff at Jishuitan Hospital also say the 12-year-old girl reportedly involved in the self-immolation died “suddenly” just before she was to be released from the hospital. They reported that her death was “very suspicious” because she had recovered well and showed good health just a day before she died. They reported that on the morning of March 17, 2001 – the day she was to be released – she was “quite animated and active” and was visited by the head of the Beijing City Medical Administration Division. A few hours later she was suddenly in critical condition and died.
Information and “loopholes” that were previously uncovered about the self-immolation incident include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRC Lies About Source of Up-Close Footage: Shortly after the incident, the Chinese regime claimed the up-close footage of the self-immolation incident, which has been widely used in anti-Falun Gong programs, was taken by a CNN news crew who were on the Square that day. However, according to a Washington Post article, CNN’s chief news executive, Eason Jordan, said “the footage used in the Chinese television reports could not have come from CNN videotape because the CNN cameraman was arrested almost immediately after the incident began.” The Post article went on to say, “The close-up shots shown on Chinese television appear to have been taken without any interference from police. In some, the camera is clearly behind police barricades …In addition, footage from overhead surveillance cameras in Tiananmen Square appears to show a man using a small handheld video camera to film the scene, not a large TV news camera.” The man with the video camera is dressed like a Chinese police officer and moving freely among them to video tape the scene at close range.
Source of Long-Range Footage Remains Unknown: The long-distance surveillance cameras located on roofs of the buildings surrounding Tiananmen Square pan back and forth automatically, and do not have the capability to zoom in and out. Yet, the long distance footage of the self-immolations was not panning at all, but focusing in on the exact locations of the self-immolations. Additionally, these cameras were zooming in and out. Who took this footage and how did they happen to be on the rooftops with a long distance zoom-capable video camera at the right time?
Footage Shows Self-Immolator Clubbed on the Head by Security Officer: From the video recording of the self-immolation aired on CCTV, one can see a man wearing a military overcoat and he appears to have a heavy object that strikes the head of Ms. Liu Chunling, one of the self-immolators. The impact of the blow sends her immediately to the ground. WOPIFG believes that it is highly likely that Liu Chunling died at the scene from this assault instead of from burns, as the Chinese regime claims. Who is this man and why did he strike Ms. Liu on the head? One theory derived from Ms. Liu’s frantic motion and reported yelling during the incident suggests she had or said something that might betray the self-immolation plot.
Immediate Availability of Fire Extinguishers: Fire extinguishers were almost immediately available, yet no police or security personnel have ever been known to carry fire extinguishers while patrolling Tiananmen Square. Who had the fire extinguishers and how did they happen to be on-hand?
Police Pause Before Draping Blanket over Victim as Near-by Camera Rolls: In the up-close footage of the incident, one can see a police officer approach one self-immolator with a fire blanket. However, the officer holds it over the self-immolator’s head and waits. Finally, the self-immolator shouts out something like “This universal dafa is something everyone has to get through,” (spokespersons for the Falun Dafa Information Center say this statement has no basis in the teachings of Falun Gong) at which point the officer than throws the blanket on the man. Why did the officer wait for the man to shout this slogan as the video camera was rolling right in front of him?
Immediate Broadcast by Chinese State-Run Media: Broadcasting news of sensitive topics typically takes many hours, and sometimes even days to finalize because it requires approval from many Party officials and censors. News of the self-immolation incident, however, was first aired within hours after the incident happened – lightening speed for China’s state-run CCTV.
Washington Post Findings about a Self-Immolator: A Washington Post reporter went to the hometown of one of the self-immolators to investigate her background. A subsequent Washington Post article reported that “none ever saw her practice.” After this article was published, the reporter was arrested upon returning to this victim’s hometown for further investigation.
In a written statement about the case, the WOIPFG says, “It is possible that this crime can be directly attributed to Jiang Zemin, the Chinese president and head of the Chinese Communist Party at the time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Jaw recognizes the gravity of the allegations his organization has made, and that if proven correct, this could be the biggest known conspiracy undertaken by the Chinese leadership since the Communist Party came to power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Mr. Jaw also says that much work remains to be done. “We recognize the degree of difficulty of the case and the importance to continue further investigation,” says Mr. Jaw. “We are determined to discover and expose all the facts surrounding this case.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://faluninfo.net/investigation-uncovers-more-lies-in-chinese-regimes-story-of-tragic-self-immolation-incident/&#34;&gt;FalunInfo.net Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/save/https://faluninfo.net/investigation-uncovers-more-lies-in-chinese-regimes-story-of-tragic-self-immolation-incident/&#34;&gt;Web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FalunInfo.net: The Tiananmen Square &#34;Self-Immolation&#34;</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/the_tiananmen_square_self_immolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2003 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/the_tiananmen_square_self_immolation/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tiananmen-square-self-immolation&#34;&gt;The Tiananmen Square &amp;ldquo;Self-Immolation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potent Hate Propaganda Turns the Tide against Falun Gong in China&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;FalunInfo.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;December 14, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 23, 2001, five individuals allegedly set themselves on fire in Tienanmen Square. Within hours, Chinese authorities flooded the state-run media with grisly photos of the event, claiming the self-immolators were Falun Gong practitioners. Days later, a Washington Post article revealed that at least two of the self-immolators had never been seen practicing Falun Gong. And further evidence uncovered in the subsequent weeks revealed the incident was staged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside China, however, where state-run media was saturated with programs accusing the Falun Gong teachings of causing the tragedy, the incident became a key tool for Chinese authorities to bend public opinion against Falun Gong. The “self-immolation” infuriated a misled public whose anger, over time, was directed toward the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas in years prior Falun Gong had generally been a house-hold name and widely respected in China, after months of media coverage of the “self-immolations,” people changed from sympathizing with the Falun Gong to attacking the practice. Hate crimes targeting Falun Gong followers increased and Jiang’s faction within the Central Government also escalated its persecution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a sampling of the details, which raises questions about the validity of the Chinese regime’s claims…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days after the incident, Washington Post reporter, Philip Pan, traveled to the hometown of two of the alleged self-immolators to investigate, finding no one had ever seen them practice Falun Gong.
Police on Tiananmen Square were carrying numerous fire extinguishers, which were used to put out the fires of the self-immolators almost immediately. According to foreign reporters that have spent years on the Square, the police there normally never carry fire extinguishers. Additionally, the self-immolators were wearing heavy, protective clothing.
Video footage taken from surveillance cameras show one policeman shooting the whole event up-close with a video camera. Again, according to reporters who have spent years covering events on the Square, the police normally don’t carry video cameras with them. The up-close footage is later used in a barrage of propaganda against Falun Gong. Chinese authorities claim the up-close footage was taken by CNN, but CNN says they have no footage from the incident because their cameras were confiscated almost immediately after the incident began.
National Taiwan University’s Speech Processing Laboratory, a world leader in the areas of Chinese language speech identification, synthesis, and verification, analyzed the voice of one of the self-immolators named Wang Jindong from a number of different interviews broadcast by China’s state-run television. The laboratory concluded that the Wang Jindong interviewed in one of the programs is a different person than the Wang Jindong appearing in the other programs, suggesting that the government hired different actors at different times.
According to the Xinhua News Agency (the Chinese government’s news agency), the self-immolation incident took place at 2:41 p.m. After adding the 7 minutes it took to put out the fires and the 20 minutes that it normally takes for a vehicle to go from Tiananmen Square to Jishuitan Hospital, the ambulance should have arrived at Jishuitan Hospital between 3:00 and 3:30 p.m. Yet several medical personnel at the hospital have confirmed that the ambulance didn’t arrive at the hospital until around 5:00 p.m. What happened during those hours of disappearance?
Award-winning Documentary
In November 2003, the English film “False Fire,” which examines the suspicious points of the Tiananmen “self-immolation” incident, won an honorary award at the 51st Columbia International Film Festival for its analytical approach and exposure of the tragic event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://faluninfo.net/the-tiananmen-square-self-immolation/&#34;&gt;FalunInfo.net link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20190205131408/http://faluninfo.net/the-tiananmen-square-self-immolation/&#34;&gt;Web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporters without Borders: The international press still prevented from covering the activities of the Falungong movement</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/international_press_prevented_from_covering_falun_gong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/international_press_prevented_from_covering_falun_gong/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reporters-without-borders-the-international-press-still-prevented-from-covering-the-activities-of-the-falungong-movement-cached-copy-1&#34;&gt;Reporters without Borders: The international press still prevented from covering the activities of the Falungong movement (Cached copy &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three journalists detained on Tiananmen Square&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Reporters without Borders&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;December 4, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 20 November 2001, Jutta Lietsch, correspondent of the German newspaper Leipziger Volkszeitung and contributor to the daily Tageszeitung, Wen-Chun Fan, cameraman of the American TV channel CNN, Stefan Niemann, correspondent of the German TV channel ARD in Beijing and her assistant were detained and questioned by the police while they were covering the demonstration of 35 Western followers of the spiritual movement Falungong on Tiananmen Square in Beijing.
The cameramen&amp;rsquo;s equipment was seized. The authorities accused the three journalists of not having requested authorization for doing this report. They were released two hours later but their equipment, particularly their films, press cards and residence permits were not returned to them. Jutta Lietsch had been invited to the Foreign Ministry in the afternoon, where she was told that the authorities would not take into account their offence if the journalists did not report the events which they had witnessed. Further to the articles published in the German press, the authorities qualified the ARD correspondent as a &amp;ldquo;troublemaker&amp;rdquo; and threatened to confiscate his press card for two months, therefore preventing him from working. The authorities also seized the press card of the CNN reporter Wen-Chun Fan, for two months. They may also take similar measures against Stefan Niemann.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporters Without Borders (RSF - Reporters sans Frontières) protested against this questioning and these threats, and the way the Chinese authorities are trying to prevent foreign journalists from reporting on Falungong activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two years the Chinese authorities have harassed foreign journalists who investigate this organization criminalized by the government. On 22 July 1999, the Beijing authorities banned the spiritual movement after charging it with being a &amp;ldquo;superstitious&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;devilish&amp;rdquo; sect. In twenty-eight months, the repression launched by the authorities has caused, according to Falungong, the death of at least two hundred and fifty people and the arrest and detention of five hundred thousand people, for varying periods of time.
Since the beginning of 1999, foreign press correspondents in China have been interested by the Falungong phenomenon, a movement inspired by Taoism, Buddhism and also by traditional Chinese meditation, Qi Gong. Full attention of the media has been focused on it since the 25 April 1999 demonstration, when thousands of Falungong followers surrounded the central government&amp;rsquo;s seat in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the eradication campaign against Falungong was launched by the authorities, foreign journalists have systematically been hindered in their work on this topic. Foreign photographers and cameramen are prevented from working on and around Tiananmen Square where hundreds of Falungong followers have demonstrated for the passed years. According to Reporters Without Borders&amp;rsquo; estimations, at least fifty representatives of international media have been questioned. Some of them have been beaten by the police. The correspondents who have tried to cover the banned movement&amp;rsquo;s activities have been harassed by the security services. Finally, many Falungong followers have been jailed for being interviewed by foreign journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The police is always present around Tiananmen Square, ready to question any photographer or cameraman who may try to capture some pictures of followers peacefully demonstrating against the ban on their movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testimonies obtained by RSF from foreign press correspondents are overwhelming for the Chinese authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threats and tailing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 28 October 1999, Falungong managed to organize an underground press conference for some international media. A dozen journalists were present, among them foreign press agencies. The Falungong speakers had enough time to explain the nature of their movement and to denounce the repression to which they were subjected. The following day, world-wide media reported this press conference - a real humiliation for the Chinese security services which wanted their revenge. The Chinese police detained five correspondents of the foreign press and seized their press cards. During long interrogations, punctuated by threats, the journalists were accused of producing &amp;ldquo;illegal reports&amp;rdquo;. They were forced to sign a letter in which they recognized having worked illegally. During the following months, the majority of the foreign journalists interested in Falungong were followed, questioned and often threatened. An American daily&amp;rsquo;s correspondent remembers: &amp;ldquo;I was constantly followed. Sometimes far, sometimes near. The policemen were very aggressive. I could not even work or visit friends because I feared causing them problems. My contacts were constantly watched and it was impossible for me to meet Falungong members for fear of their arrest.&amp;rdquo; Another journalist based in Beijing denounced these practices which still force him to &amp;ldquo;leave home by the back door, to hide in the taxi, and to check a thousand times if we are not being followed before meeting someone&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transmitting information, particularly to foreign journalists working in Beijing, also caused several followers to be jailed. Zhan Xueling, quoted in a series of articles by Ian Johnson, the Wall Street Journal correspondent in Beijing, was arrested by the police on 24 April 2001. She was sentenced to three years in a labour camp a few weeks later. The American daily&amp;rsquo;s journalist had reported in an article, awarded with the Pulitzer Prize, that the young woman accused the police of Shandong province (east of the country) of beating to death her mother, also a Falungong member. Ian Johnson did not confirm that Zhan Xueling&amp;rsquo;s arrest was linked to his article, but he is sure that after receiving the Pulitzer Prize for his articles about Falungong, the &amp;ldquo;Chinese police are likely to make my life impossible in Beijing&amp;rdquo;. He is now a correspondent in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gu Linna, a Falungong member, was sentenced to four years in jail for transmitting information to foreign journalists about hundreds of members forced to undergo psychiatric internment. This former presenter of Hebei province TV channel also took part in the organization of press conferences for foreign journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning and violence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last two years dozens of journalists, among them photographers and press agency cameramen, have been questioned by the police while trying to cover Falungong activities in Beijing. About twenty reporters of Agence France-Presse have been arrested by the police. AFP, Reuters, AP and CNN have all been ejected from the square more or less violently or subjected to processing through police vans converted into mobile police stations. The foreign press is therefore &amp;ldquo;persona non grata&amp;rdquo; on and around Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A photographer of a foreign press agency in Beijing who is a native of China is systematically chased away from Tiananmen Square. A French reporter of a press agency, questioned in 2000 on Tiananmen Square, was deprived of his press card for more than ten days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A photographer for a press agency reports: &amp;ldquo;For the first demonstrations we decided to be permanently present on the spot. We took turns. As soon as a Falungong group started a demonstration, the policemen were looking for any person with cameras or video cameras. You had to be fast to avoid the questioning. When they catch you, they first open your equipment and then take your press card. If you are lucky, it can last a few hours, or several weeks. In any case, they prevent you from working.&amp;rdquo; In June 2001, Stephen Shaver, an AFP photographer, was questioned and hit by policemen during the concert of &amp;ldquo;The Three Tenors&amp;rdquo; in favour of the Beijing bid for the 2008 Olympics while he was photographing the arrest of a person by the police. As usual, the Chinese authorities charged the photographer with &amp;ldquo;illegal work&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, Teresa Bergada, journalist of the Spanish radio station Radio Catalunya, was detained and hit by the police in 2000, after taking pictures of the arrest of Falungong members in Beijing. The Spanish embassy had to intervene to secure the journalist&amp;rsquo;s release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreign television teams which manage to take pictures of the repression against Falungong face another problem. The government television channel Central Television of China, the only channel able to send pictures abroad by satellite, has blocked the broadcasting of pictures concerning Falungong, on order from the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repression against Falungong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1999 Falungong has used modern techniques to communicate. Meetings and demonstrations have been organized through mobile phones and e-mails. Falungong has launched web sites and radio stations from abroad. The authorities have reacted very violently by trying to take punitive measures against those who transmit information and by preventing followers from contacting others groups abroad. For about two years the Falungong web sites have been banned in China and visiting them is liable to a jail sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad treatment attributed to the security forces has caused the death of at least two Falungong members who took part in the diffusion or the copying of information about the group drawn from the Internet.
On 27 June 2001, Li Changjun died after being tortured in police custody. He was arrested on 16 May for having downloaded and printed Internet documents about Falungong. According to the Information Centre for Human Rights and Democracy, based in Hong Kong, Li Changjun, 33, worked for the Wuhan tax centre, in Hubei province (central China), and had already been arrested several times for maintaining his membership with the &amp;ldquo;harmful sect&amp;rdquo;, as the authorities call it. Li Changjun&amp;rsquo;s mother said that her son was covered with scars and nasty bruises, that his neck and his ears were purplish and that he was abnormally thin.
On 1 August 2001, Chen Qiulan, 47, member of Falungong, died of a heart attack in the detention centre of Daging (province of Heilongjiang, north-east of the country). He had been arrested in July 2001 for spreading information on the Internet about the movement.
Otherwise, the professor Chang was sentenced to three years in jail for having sent information to a Falungong radio station based abroad. He was found guilty of &amp;ldquo;diffusing state secrets&amp;rdquo;. He actually reported the repression on the movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These violations of press freedom are unacceptable. China&amp;rsquo;s determination to prevent the foreign press from covering the activities and government repression of the Falungong clearly illustrates its rejection of independent news gathering.
In that way, the Chinese communist Party denies the foreign press the right to cover difference of opinion, corruption, AIDS in Henan province, natural disasters, Tibetan and Uighur separatism and, finally, Falungong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporters Without Borders has asked the Chinese government to stop intimidation against foreign journalists who attempt to inform international public opinion about the Falungong situation in China. &amp;ldquo;China committed itself vis-à-vis the international community to let journalists work freely during the 2008 Olympics in Beijing. The authorities should anticipate this generous promise and stop hindering foreign press correspondents&amp;rdquo;, Robert Ménard, RSF general secretary, declared. Before the next session of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, Reporters Without Borders will appeal to the special rapporteur for free expression to denounce the Chinese authorities&amp;rsquo; attitude towards foreign journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20050227225628/http://www.rsf.org/rsf/uk/html/asie/cplp01/cp01/041201.html&#34;&gt;Web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The link to the original article is no longer available. The above is a cached copy of the original article.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danny Schechter, Washington Post: The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing?</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fires-this-time-immolation-or-deception-in-beijing&#34;&gt;The Fires This Time: Immolation Or Deception In Beijing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danny_Schechter&#34;&gt;Danny Schechter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 22, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could be more dramatic? People are setting themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square in the heart of Beijing. CNN is there. The police just happen to have fire extinguishers on hand, and the victims are rushed to a hospital after their agonies are thoroughly photographed for state television. While the government-controlled media uncharacteristically releases the story at once, it takes a week of production before video footage is aired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, horrific images are rocketed around the world, seeming to confirm China&amp;rsquo;s charges that an evil cult is ordering brainwashed members to commit suicide. Citing this new &amp;ldquo;evidence,&amp;rdquo; the government insists that what it has been saying all along about those &amp;ldquo;fanatical&amp;rdquo; Falun Gongers is true, and these people must be banned as a threat to themselves and the nation. On February 16 another suicide is attributed to Falun Gong. Alongside a charred body an uncharred note is found allegedly claiming the victim did it to support Li Hongzhi&amp;rsquo;s spiritual practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal&amp;rsquo;s Ian Johnson, one of the most insightful journalists following this story, had his suspicions aroused by the speed with which this story was covered, observing that the state media &amp;ldquo;reported [the victim&amp;rsquo;s] death with unusual alacrity, implying that either the death took place earlier than reported or the usually cautious media had top-level approval to rush out electronic reports and a televised dispatch. The 7 p.m. local evening news, for example, had a filmed report from Mr. Tan&amp;rsquo;s hometown of Changde, a small city in Hunan province. Most reports for the evening news are vetted by noon, so the daily broadcast rarely carries reports from the same day, let alone an event that happened at noon and involved satellite feeds from relatively remote parts of the country.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For news readers and media consumers, perception often trumps unclear realities. In a world where dramatic images overshadow complex issues, Falun Gong stands convicted of crazed cult behavior. Case closed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score a big one for Chinese President Jiang Zemin&amp;rsquo;s crusade to &amp;ldquo;crush&amp;rdquo; and discredit a growing spiritual movement that continues to resist a state-ordered ban despite the detention of an estimated 50,000 practitioners and over a hundred dead in police custody. Already, on the strength of this one incident, The Financial Times proclaimed a &amp;ldquo;winner,&amp;rdquo; as in, &amp;ldquo;Beijing Wins Propaganda War Against Falun Gong.&amp;rdquo; Note the headline. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t refer merely to one skirmish in a protracted media war that has gone on for 19 months, but to the war itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many other respected news organizations disseminated the same story the same way even though they were unable to verify it independently, instead using accounts from Communist Party-controlled state media, especially the Xinua news agency. Now, as new questions are raised and doubts expressed, it may turn out that the world media have been misled into becoming an uncritical transmission belt for Beijing&amp;rsquo;s bullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firing Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first incident happened on January 23, days after Jiang intensified his official, nationwide, anti-cult media campaign. CNN was in the Square and reported on the suicides but its tapes were confiscated, so we never saw them. Seven days later, China&amp;rsquo;s official TV shocked the nation with footage of five people engulfed in flames, pictures said to be from nearby surveillance cameras. Now a tragically disfigured victim of the incident, 12-year-old Liu Siying, says that her own mother told her to set herself on fire to reach the &amp;ldquo;heavenly golden kingdom&amp;rdquo; in some accounts, or &amp;ldquo;nirvana&amp;rdquo; in others. She has become a sympathetic symbol, even a poster child for alleged abuses by the &amp;ldquo;evil cult.&amp;rdquo; Her image is everywhere; her tragedy has outraged all China. (In this respect she is the Elian Gonzalez of China!) Yet only approved media outlets there have been permitted access to her. Western reporters have been barred from direct contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was she a Falun Gong practitioner? That seems doubtful, after The Washington Post&amp;rsquo;s Phillip Pan traced her to her home in Kaifeng (a town that experienced an even more tragic disco fire recently, killing hundreds and scarring many others). Pan discovered that the young girl&amp;rsquo;s mother, who died in the Tiananmen fire, was not known locally as a practitioner, but was depressed, mentally unstable and accused of beating her daughter and mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significantly, one of the CNN producers on the scene, just 50 feet away, says she did not even see a child there. The government says doctors performed a tracheotomy on the victim, but a pediatric surgeon said that, if that were true, the child wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be speaking right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong spokespeople have been quoted as denying that they ordered, orchestrated and participated in this incident. But in their statement, which has not been carried in full anywhere, they go further and indict the Western press: &amp;ldquo;It is troubling to us that the party line from the PRC [People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China] mouthpieces, Xinhua News Agency and CCTV, is being given so much airtime and so much credibility by the foreign press. Xinhua and other state-run media outlets are generally never considered credible sources, as even they openly admit that their function is to disseminate propaganda for the Chinese regime. In fact, Xinhua is the Party line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is so much that remains unclear and unknown about the circumstances surrounding the incident. And no one knows what occurred in the week after the actual event and before the Chinese media outlets finally released their fully engineered news articles and television programs. We must remember that the Chinese regime is so tightly controlling every aspect of this case that none of Xinhua&amp;rsquo;s claims have been corroborated by independent sources.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why would Falun Gong deny its role in the incident if it was a protest? The Longhai Foundation, which monitors Chinese prisons, had similar questions in the National Review: &amp;ldquo;Was this event staged or allowed to happen by China&amp;rsquo;s government in order to discredit the Falun Gong? It is hardly a farfetched hypothesis. China&amp;rsquo;s government has promised to extinguish all problems connected with the Falun Gong in advance of the 80th anniversary of Chinese Communism, which Beijing plans on celebrating this July. &amp;hellip; Justin Yu, a journalist for World Journal, the Chinese-language daily, reflected on the confusion faced by many Chinese over what to believe. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s propaganda coup against the Falun Gong relies upon people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of events in recent Asian history, such as the 73-year-old Buddhist monk in Saigon whose self-immolation was a form of protest to fulfill his beliefs, [like] Koreans cutting off their fingers and the Japanese ritual of hari-kari. But this situation is not clear. Who do we believe — the Communists? They have lied to us so many times, another lie for them is nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Beatrice Turpin who covered Falun Gong in China for Associated Press TV and wrote about her experiences for MediaChannel what her suspicion was. She responded from her home in Thailand: &amp;ldquo;There was a big brouhaha with Falun Gong protests and footage of police beating practitioners last Chinese New Year and it would certainly fit in with typical China strategy to stage an event this year and make the show their own.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grounds for Skepticism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong practitioners initially told me their suspicions were aroused for three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the people in the Square, said to be long-time practitioners, didn&amp;rsquo;t do the Falun Gong exercises correctly;
authorities did not show any pictures or Falun Gong signs or books (which prohibit suicide) that protesters usually bring with them into the Square; and
a school one of the victims was said to have graduated from was in fact closed at the time. They also say that there is no concept of &amp;ldquo;nirvana&amp;rdquo; in their beliefs.
These are perhaps small details, but they may be telling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Falun Gong pointed to other inconsistencies: &amp;ldquo;Xinhua News Agency claims that within a minute of the man setting himself ablaze, police had dashed over to him with four fire extinguishers and quickly put out the flames. A European journalist based in Beijing, however, told us: &amp;ldquo;I have never seen policemen patrolling on Tiananmen Square carrying fire extinguishers. How come they all showed up today? The location of the incident is at least 20 minutes roundtrip from the nearest building — the People&amp;rsquo;s Great Hall. If they were to have dashed over there to get the equipment, it would have been too late.&amp;rdquo; Is it even possible that the police could have responded with not one but four fire extinguishers within the space of a minute if they didn&amp;rsquo;t have prior knowledge that this was going to occur?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In terms of response time, another foreign journalist in Beijing expressed shock that Xinhua was able to release the first report on the incident almost immediately and in English, no less. Every Chinese citizen knows that every report from Xinhua usually has to first go through several rounds of approval by higher-ups and is generally &amp;lsquo;old news&amp;rsquo; by the time it is published. Moreover, state-run media have never released any photos or video of Falun Gong protests in the course of 18 months of persecution to the foreign press, so why now and with so little hesitation? And why only in English and not in Chinese?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue was raised with me again and again during a recent four-city tour speaking about my new book on the Falun Gong. Some people told me Falun Gong must be crazy if it does crazy things. When I challenged the assumption that we in fact know all the details, eyes glazed over. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because once people hear &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo; that seem to confirm their own assumptions, they don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear more, even if the original &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo; may be wrong or misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot images sear themselves into the brain; retractions and clarifications rarely do. In the newly published Tiananmen Papers, on how the Communist Party handled the student protests in 1989, journalist Orville Schell, dean of the Journalism School at Berkeley, discusses the many forgeries and falsehoods the Chinese government and others have concocted and circulated over the years. Disinformation and misinformation are the trade craft of intelligence agencies in many countries, especially China. It is not surprising that Beijing is denouncing these new documents as fake. Clearly, their publication is embarrassing to the secretive rulers of China, especially President Jiang Zemin, whose hard-line role in those events has been revived in the official persecution of Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Are The Skeptics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did the deeply ingrained, institutionalized skepticism of our own media crumble so quickly in the face of what smells like a stage-managed incident that&amp;rsquo;s being blatantly exploited for political reasons? Why would so many American news outlets be so gullible? Is it because the whiff of spirituality and mysticism in a culture few of us understand makes some of us uncomfortable in our journalistic practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my investigation into Falun Gong, I document a disturbing pattern of U.S. media outlets echoing China&amp;rsquo;s charges, including the frequent use of pejorative words like &amp;ldquo;cult&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sect&amp;rdquo; and even &amp;ldquo;mishmash.&amp;rdquo; In some respects the media in our own country also reflect a one-dimensional, stereotyped perspective, downplaying and denigrating a force that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit into simple left-right political categories and which they may have trouble relating to because of its Asian character and roots in a mix of a Buddhist cultivation practice, Taoism and traditional qigong. Falun Gong is too often treated like the classic &amp;ldquo;other,&amp;rdquo; too weird to be taken seriously or show sympathy toward. (Incidentally, I am not a Falun Gong practitioner, but our company has produced videos for Falun Gong, which gave me access and information I used to write and produce a film and a book on the subject.&amp;ldquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one of my bookstore appearances in Chicago, someone compared Falun Gong and the current situation in China to David Koresh&amp;rsquo;s Branch Davidians and the 51-day siege in 1993 by federal law enforcement officers in Waco, ostensibly to seize guns and protect children from abuse, a comparison China has invoked to make the case that it&amp;rsquo;s only doing what the U.S. government did in combating its own dangerous cult. Someone jumped up to challenge the analogy, arguing that Koresh and company were violent and Falun Gong is not. He was right: There is no direct comparison, except in terms of the response to what happened. Only the hard right-wing in the United States criticized the government&amp;rsquo;s brutal military intervention, which reminded me of the words of that American lieutenant in Vietnam: &amp;ldquo;We destroyed the village in order to save it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of empathy people felt for the families under Koresh&amp;rsquo;s mad control led to many rationalizing or not speaking out against the bloody and illegal suppression that occurred in Waco. Once people are dehumanized in our eyes, we may lose compassion for them and turn the other way when their rights are violated, especially if we dislike their politics and consider them unsympathetic victims. If you want to know the details of where dehumanization leads in China, check out Amnesty International&amp;rsquo;s recent report on the pervasive use of torture, which is often directed at nonviolent Falun Gong practitioners. Beijing, natch, calls that a forgery too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 17, more than a thousand Falun Gong practitioners protested nonviolently in Los Angeles against the persecution going on in China. Few media outlets showed up at their press conference, even though this is a story making headlines worldwide. (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any story about it the next day in The Los Angeles Times, although their book review carried a discussion of what happened in Tiananmen Square in l989.) Media indifference fans public indifference. China&amp;rsquo;s media are doing what you would expect, but how to explain the attitude of the Western media, which has covered the story so episodically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the prominent media play this &amp;ldquo;mass suicide&amp;rdquo; story received, it is not too late to thoroughly investigate not only what happened but whether and why we were all taken in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20021202162929/http://www.mediachannel.org/views/dissector/falungong2.shtml&#34;&gt;Web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Noonan: Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/beijing_is_burning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/beijing_is_burning/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beijing-is-burning-more-lies-from-the-prc&#34;&gt;Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Ann Noonan&lt;/strong&gt;, Policy Director for the Laogai Foundation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 13, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caught up in its desperate bid to host the 2008 Olympic Games, Beijing is a city in turmoil. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s insistence on soi-disant &amp;ldquo;social and political stability&amp;rdquo; has allowed it to resort to old Communist tactics reminiscent of Chairman Mao. No group knows this better than the Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, on the eve of the Chinese New Year, seven people described as Falun Gong members reportedly tried to commit suicide in Tiananmen Square. Five of the seven succeeded in setting themselves on fire, leaving one woman dead from her injuries and four others severely burned, including the deceased&amp;rsquo;s 12 year-old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was this event staged or allowed to happen by China&amp;rsquo;s government in order to discredit the Falun Gong? It is hardly a far-fetched hypothesis. China&amp;rsquo;s government has promised to extinguish all problems connected with the Falun Gong in advance of the 80th anniversary of Chinese Communism, which Beijing plans on celebrating this July. It has already gone to great lengths to crack down on the banned spiritual movement, accusing it of being a dangerous and wicked cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of Falun Gong practitioners have been hauled off to laogai camps. Still others have been locked up in mental hospitals without the benefit of due process, and at least 140 more have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its intensifying campaign to discredit the sect, China&amp;rsquo;s leaders have now seized on a new target: the Western media. Beijing maintains that several American journalists, including two from CNN, are being investigated on possible murder charges relating to last month&amp;rsquo;s burnings in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report in The Yangcheng Evening News entitled, &amp;ldquo;Witnessing a Mother and Child Self-Immolate and Doing Nothing&amp;ndash;Exactly What Was the Role of Western Journalists?&amp;rdquo; read like a bulletin from Orwell&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Truth. It claimed that &amp;ldquo;unidentified police officials&amp;rdquo; had evidence showing that a few foreign reporters were told in advance that a dramatic Falun Gong event was to take place at the Square on January 23rd. The article said that legal actions would be taken on the murder charge of &amp;ldquo;instigating and abetting a suicide&amp;rdquo; if it could be confirmed the reporters had in fact participated in the planning of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, according to multiple reports, the only foreign reporters who actually witnessed the events included a producer and cameraman for CNN, and both of them say they had received no advance warning of the incident in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, while the Chinese media have been quick to excoriate Western journalists, they have breathlessly exonerated Beijing&amp;rsquo;s police. And yet, the police had clearly been at the ready with fire extinguishers when the self-immolators started the blaze. And in a move unmistakenly designed to rally enmity toward the Falun Gong, PRC officials hastily arranged an interview with the wounded 12 year-old. This poor child, who had suffered large-scale burn injuries, was shepherded into an official interview immediately after undergoing a tracheotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, New York&amp;rsquo;s Falun Dafa Information Center steadfastly rejects reports that the Beijing burn victims were true members of the sect. The deceased woman had never been known to practice Falun Gong exercises; nor had she openly associated herself with the movement. More importantly, the essential teachings of Falun Gong explicitly forbid violence of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also speculation that the burn victims may have sacrificed themselves as a form of desperate protestation against the Communist regime. Justin Yu, a journalist for World Journal, the Chinese-language daily, reflected on the confusion faced by many Chinese over what to believe. &amp;ldquo;The PRC&amp;rsquo;s propaganda coup against the Falun Gong relies upon people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of events in recent Asian history, such as the 73 year-old Buddhist monk in Saigon whose self-immolating is a form of protest to fulfill his beliefs, [like] Koreans cutting off their fingers, and the Japanese ritual of hari-kari. But this situation is not clear. Who do we believe&amp;ndash;the Communists? They have lied to us so many times, another lie for them is nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, one wonders why the Falun Gong would deny its participation if it had organized the burning event as a form of protest? According to the human-rights activist Ann Lau, &amp;ldquo;The PRC is using its same old tactics even though they did not work in the past. For example, China&amp;rsquo;s government insists that there was no famine in the late &amp;lsquo;50s and early &amp;lsquo;60s, yet that famine took 30 million lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been noted that some hard-liners are not even attempting to camouflage their Mao-style tactics. New York Times reporter Erik Eckholm recently quoted (from an article in China&amp;rsquo;s Legal Daily) an old slogan that describes Falun Gong followers as the &amp;ldquo;running dogs of foreign anti-Chinese forces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is wrenching to think that all it took to reinvigorate Beijing&amp;rsquo;s propaganda machine was a few simple breathing exercises. China&amp;rsquo;s war on the Falun Gong revitalizes Mao&amp;rsquo;s dream: to let no aspect of Chinese society escape the party&amp;rsquo;s grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are the 2008 Olympics worth all that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20131029202638/http://old.nationalreview.com/comment/commentprint021301a.html&#34;&gt;Web Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philip Pan, Washington Post: Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery (F)</title>
      <link>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefiresite.github.io/falsefire.com/fr/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery&#34;&gt;Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong (Excerpts &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Philip P. Pan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 4, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KAIFENG, China (Washington Post Foreign Service) — There is a neighborhood on the eastern side of this once-glorious city called Apple Orchard, but there are no apple trees here, only drab concrete buildings and clusters of unemployed men loitering on mud streets. It was here, in a fourth-floor apartment in Building Six, that Liu Chunling and her 12-year-old daughter, Liu Siying, lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mother was a quiet woman who kept to herself, the daughter a lively fifth-grader who never failed to smile and say hello. Neighbors recalled there was something both strange and sad about Liu Chunling, that she sometimes hit her child, that she drove her elderly mother away, that she worked in a nightclub and took money to keep men company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one suspected that Liu, 36, might have joined the banned spiritual movement Falun Gong. And hardly anyone noticed when she and her daughter disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there they were on national television, their bodies engulfed in orange flames in Tiananmen Square. Liu Siying was shown lying on a stretcher, her face and lips charred black, whimpering, “Mama, mama.” Her mother, the newscast reported, was already dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drove the Lius and three others from this city in central Henan province, about 350 miles south of Beijing, to pour gasoline on their bodies and set themselves afire on Jan. 23, the eve of the Chinese New Year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An intense battle is underway to answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ruling Communist Party has launched an all-out campaign to use the incident to turn public opinion in China and abroad against the group it outlawed 18 months ago and has tried to crush, at times with brutal tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning and night, the state-controlled media carry fresh attacks against Falun Gong and its U.S.-based leader, Li Hongzhi. Schools have been ordered to “educate” pupils about the sect. Discussion meetings have been organized in factories, offices and universities. Religious leaders as far away as Tibet have delivered scripted denunciations. In Kaifeng, the post office issued an anti-Falun Gong postmark, and 10,000 people signed a public petition against the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has also used the incident to pressure Hong Kong to ban Falun Gong, testing the strength of the “one country, two systems” setup that gives the former British colony autonomy over its affairs. Falun Gong exists legally in Hong Kong, but the territory’s security chief warned Thursday that police intend to monitor the group’s activities closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong leaders insist that the Lius and their companions could not have been members of their movement, which promotes a mix of Buddhism, Taoism and traditional Chinese breathing exercises. They have said Falun Gong clearly forbids both violence and suicide and have suggested the government may have staged the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other human rights activists say the five set themselves on fire to protest the government’s crackdown on Falun Gong, which has resulted in thousands of arrests and as many as 105 deaths in police custody. All but 12-year-old Liu Siying had protested Beijing’s actions against Falun Gong in Tiananmen Square previously, according to the Hong Kong-based Information Center for Human Rights and Democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a tradition of politically motivated suicide in China. At the start of China’s last dynasty, in the 1640s, hundreds of people killed themselves rather than live under the conquering Manchus. More than 250 years later, several students committed suicide to protest the Qing Dynasty’s refusal to establish a constitutional republic. Most recently, countless Chinese took their lives to escape the abuse of Mao Zedong’s Cultural Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is hardly any precedent for public self-immolation. In Kaifeng, a city of 700,000 that was China’s imperial capital and one of the world’s most populous cities at the turn of the last millennium, most residents took a dim view of what Liu and the others did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They disgraced Kaifeng, and they disgraced China in front of the whole world. It was just too much!” said Tang Shaohua, 60, who runs a grocery around the corner from Liu’s home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so sad what happened to that little girl. I used to see her playing around here,” added neighbor Zhang Binglian, 60. “Falun Gong is an evil cult. I thought that before, and I’m even more convinced now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in Kaifeng, there are signs that the government’s propaganda campaigns have lost some of their effectiveness. Several residents expressed weariness with the barrage against Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not saying I don’t believe the government, but I’m not saying I believe it, either,” said Liu Xiaoyu, 39, as she made dumplings in Kaifeng’s lively night market. “The government controls the news. We all know that now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cab driver Wang Chaohui said he believed Falun Gong was a religion like any other, and said it would be unfair to blame the acts of five individuals on a group with millions of practitioners. In any case, he said, the crackdown on Falun Gong was sure to backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“China is different now, and they can’t arrest everybody who believes in something like this,” he said. “It only makes things worse.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wang said the real question China must confront is why so many people believe in something like Falun Gong. “People are dissatisfied with society,” he said. “That’s the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the rest of China, Kaifeng has experienced a revival in all kinds of religions as communist ideology has lost its appeal. Over the past decade, residents have turned in large numbers to Christianity, Buddhism, Taoism — and Falun Gong. Before the group was banned, hundreds practiced its meditation exercises in the city’s parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong has attracted a cross section of Chinese — party members, senior army officers, bureaucrats, teachers and millions living on the margins of society. In Kaifeng, where several factories have closed and the economy has slumped, many are searching for something to believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state media have said little about why the five who set themselves on fire might have joined Falun Gong. Beijing denied requests to interview Liu Siying and the three other survivors, who are all hospitalized with serious burns. A Kaifeng official said only China Central Television and the official New China News Agency were permitted to speak to their relatives or their colleagues. A man who answered the door at the Liu home referred questions to the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Liu Chunling’s Apple Orchard neighbors described her as a woman who led a troubled life and suffered from psychological problems. State media identified 78-year-old Hao Xiuzhen as her adoptive mother. Neighbors said they quarreled often before Liu drove the woman from their home last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was something wrong with her,” said neighbor Liu Min, 51. “She hit her mother, and her mother was crying and yelling. She hit her daughter, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also questions about how Liu supported herself and about the whereabouts of her daughter’s father. Neighbors said Liu was not a native of Kaifeng, and that a man in southern Guangdong province paid her rent. Others, including neighbor Wen Jian, 22, said Liu worked in a local nightclub and was paid to dine with and dance with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None ever saw her practice Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/?utm_term=.e0b129d43a6c&#34;&gt;Washington Post Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://faluninfo.net/washington-post-human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery-excerpts/&#34;&gt;Falun Info Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The above are excerpts from the original article from The Washington Post, which you can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
