<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>False Fire Homepage on 偽火</title>
    <link>/zh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in False Fire Homepage on 偽火</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/zh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>關於《偽火》視頻</title>
      <link>/zh/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/about/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;關於-偽火-电视纪录片&#34;&gt;關於《偽火》电视纪录片&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;北美非盈利中文電視臺“新唐人”製作的纪录片《偽火》（False Fire）分析2001年天安門自焚事件。該片獲第51屆哥倫布國際電影電視節榮譽獎。頒獎儀式于11月8日在俄亥俄州哥倫布市的隔路藝術設計學院坎薩中心舉行。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在《偽火》這部影片中，新唐人電視臺製作人分析了中國中央電視臺自焚報道的漏洞，揭示天安門自焚事件極有可能是中國江氏政府为栽贓法輪功、並為鎮壓法輪功製造藉口而炮製的一起偽案。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>媒體頻道: 這次的火焰 - 自焚還是北京的欺騙?</title>
      <link>/zh/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/reports/the_fire_this_time_immolation_or_deception_in_beijing/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;這次的火焰-自焚還是北京的欺騙&#34;&gt;這次的火焰 - 自焚還是北京的欺騙?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Danny_Schechter&#34;&gt;丹尼.斯科且爾&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2001年2月22日&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could be more dramatic? People are setting themselves on fire in Tiananmen Square in the heart of Beijing. CNN is there. The police just happen to have fire extinguishers on hand, and the victims are rushed to a hospital after their agonies are thoroughly photographed for state television. While the government-controlled media uncharacteristically releases the story at once, it takes a week of production before video footage is aired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, horrific images are rocketed around the world, seeming to confirm China&amp;rsquo;s charges that an evil cult is ordering brainwashed members to commit suicide. Citing this new &amp;ldquo;evidence,&amp;rdquo; the government insists that what it has been saying all along about those &amp;ldquo;fanatical&amp;rdquo; Falun Gongers is true, and these people must be banned as a threat to themselves and the nation. On February 16 another suicide is attributed to Falun Gong. Alongside a charred body an uncharred note is found allegedly claiming the victim did it to support Li Hongzhi&amp;rsquo;s spiritual practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal&amp;rsquo;s Ian Johnson, one of the most insightful journalists following this story, had his suspicions aroused by the speed with which this story was covered, observing that the state media &amp;ldquo;reported [the victim&amp;rsquo;s] death with unusual alacrity, implying that either the death took place earlier than reported or the usually cautious media had top-level approval to rush out electronic reports and a televised dispatch. The 7 p.m. local evening news, for example, had a filmed report from Mr. Tan&amp;rsquo;s hometown of Changde, a small city in Hunan province. Most reports for the evening news are vetted by noon, so the daily broadcast rarely carries reports from the same day, let alone an event that happened at noon and involved satellite feeds from relatively remote parts of the country.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For news readers and media consumers, perception often trumps unclear realities. In a world where dramatic images overshadow complex issues, Falun Gong stands convicted of crazed cult behavior. Case closed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score a big one for Chinese President Jiang Zemin&amp;rsquo;s crusade to &amp;ldquo;crush&amp;rdquo; and discredit a growing spiritual movement that continues to resist a state-ordered ban despite the detention of an estimated 50,000 practitioners and over a hundred dead in police custody. Already, on the strength of this one incident, The Financial Times proclaimed a &amp;ldquo;winner,&amp;rdquo; as in, &amp;ldquo;Beijing Wins Propaganda War Against Falun Gong.&amp;rdquo; Note the headline. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t refer merely to one skirmish in a protracted media war that has gone on for 19 months, but to the war itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many other respected news organizations disseminated the same story the same way even though they were unable to verify it independently, instead using accounts from Communist Party-controlled state media, especially the Xinua news agency. Now, as new questions are raised and doubts expressed, it may turn out that the world media have been misled into becoming an uncritical transmission belt for Beijing&amp;rsquo;s bullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firing Line&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first incident happened on January 23, days after Jiang intensified his official, nationwide, anti-cult media campaign. CNN was in the Square and reported on the suicides but its tapes were confiscated, so we never saw them. Seven days later, China&amp;rsquo;s official TV shocked the nation with footage of five people engulfed in flames, pictures said to be from nearby surveillance cameras. Now a tragically disfigured victim of the incident, 12-year-old Liu Siying, says that her own mother told her to set herself on fire to reach the &amp;ldquo;heavenly golden kingdom&amp;rdquo; in some accounts, or &amp;ldquo;nirvana&amp;rdquo; in others. She has become a sympathetic symbol, even a poster child for alleged abuses by the &amp;ldquo;evil cult.&amp;rdquo; Her image is everywhere; her tragedy has outraged all China. (In this respect she is the Elian Gonzalez of China!) Yet only approved media outlets there have been permitted access to her. Western reporters have been barred from direct contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was she a Falun Gong practitioner? That seems doubtful, after The Washington Post&amp;rsquo;s Phillip Pan traced her to her home in Kaifeng (a town that experienced an even more tragic disco fire recently, killing hundreds and scarring many others). Pan discovered that the young girl&amp;rsquo;s mother, who died in the Tiananmen fire, was not known locally as a practitioner, but was depressed, mentally unstable and accused of beating her daughter and mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significantly, one of the CNN producers on the scene, just 50 feet away, says she did not even see a child there. The government says doctors performed a tracheotomy on the victim, but a pediatric surgeon said that, if that were true, the child wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be speaking right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong spokespeople have been quoted as denying that they ordered, orchestrated and participated in this incident. But in their statement, which has not been carried in full anywhere, they go further and indict the Western press: &amp;ldquo;It is troubling to us that the party line from the PRC [People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China] mouthpieces, Xinhua News Agency and CCTV, is being given so much airtime and so much credibility by the foreign press. Xinhua and other state-run media outlets are generally never considered credible sources, as even they openly admit that their function is to disseminate propaganda for the Chinese regime. In fact, Xinhua is the Party line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is so much that remains unclear and unknown about the circumstances surrounding the incident. And no one knows what occurred in the week after the actual event and before the Chinese media outlets finally released their fully engineered news articles and television programs. We must remember that the Chinese regime is so tightly controlling every aspect of this case that none of Xinhua&amp;rsquo;s claims have been corroborated by independent sources.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why would Falun Gong deny its role in the incident if it was a protest? The Longhai Foundation, which monitors Chinese prisons, had similar questions in the National Review: &amp;ldquo;Was this event staged or allowed to happen by China&amp;rsquo;s government in order to discredit the Falun Gong? It is hardly a farfetched hypothesis. China&amp;rsquo;s government has promised to extinguish all problems connected with the Falun Gong in advance of the 80th anniversary of Chinese Communism, which Beijing plans on celebrating this July. &amp;hellip; Justin Yu, a journalist for World Journal, the Chinese-language daily, reflected on the confusion faced by many Chinese over what to believe. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s propaganda coup against the Falun Gong relies upon people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of events in recent Asian history, such as the 73-year-old Buddhist monk in Saigon whose self-immolation was a form of protest to fulfill his beliefs, [like] Koreans cutting off their fingers and the Japanese ritual of hari-kari. But this situation is not clear. Who do we believe — the Communists? They have lied to us so many times, another lie for them is nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Beatrice Turpin who covered Falun Gong in China for Associated Press TV and wrote about her experiences for MediaChannel what her suspicion was. She responded from her home in Thailand: &amp;ldquo;There was a big brouhaha with Falun Gong protests and footage of police beating practitioners last Chinese New Year and it would certainly fit in with typical China strategy to stage an event this year and make the show their own.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grounds for Skepticism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong practitioners initially told me their suspicions were aroused for three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the people in the Square, said to be long-time practitioners, didn&amp;rsquo;t do the Falun Gong exercises correctly;
authorities did not show any pictures or Falun Gong signs or books (which prohibit suicide) that protesters usually bring with them into the Square; and
a school one of the victims was said to have graduated from was in fact closed at the time. They also say that there is no concept of &amp;ldquo;nirvana&amp;rdquo; in their beliefs.
These are perhaps small details, but they may be telling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a press release, Falun Gong pointed to other inconsistencies: &amp;ldquo;Xinhua News Agency claims that within a minute of the man setting himself ablaze, police had dashed over to him with four fire extinguishers and quickly put out the flames. A European journalist based in Beijing, however, told us: &amp;ldquo;I have never seen policemen patrolling on Tiananmen Square carrying fire extinguishers. How come they all showed up today? The location of the incident is at least 20 minutes roundtrip from the nearest building — the People&amp;rsquo;s Great Hall. If they were to have dashed over there to get the equipment, it would have been too late.&amp;rdquo; Is it even possible that the police could have responded with not one but four fire extinguishers within the space of a minute if they didn&amp;rsquo;t have prior knowledge that this was going to occur?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In terms of response time, another foreign journalist in Beijing expressed shock that Xinhua was able to release the first report on the incident almost immediately and in English, no less. Every Chinese citizen knows that every report from Xinhua usually has to first go through several rounds of approval by higher-ups and is generally &amp;lsquo;old news&amp;rsquo; by the time it is published. Moreover, state-run media have never released any photos or video of Falun Gong protests in the course of 18 months of persecution to the foreign press, so why now and with so little hesitation? And why only in English and not in Chinese?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue was raised with me again and again during a recent four-city tour speaking about my new book on the Falun Gong. Some people told me Falun Gong must be crazy if it does crazy things. When I challenged the assumption that we in fact know all the details, eyes glazed over. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because once people hear &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo; that seem to confirm their own assumptions, they don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear more, even if the original &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo; may be wrong or misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot images sear themselves into the brain; retractions and clarifications rarely do. In the newly published Tiananmen Papers, on how the Communist Party handled the student protests in 1989, journalist Orville Schell, dean of the Journalism School at Berkeley, discusses the many forgeries and falsehoods the Chinese government and others have concocted and circulated over the years. Disinformation and misinformation are the trade craft of intelligence agencies in many countries, especially China. It is not surprising that Beijing is denouncing these new documents as fake. Clearly, their publication is embarrassing to the secretive rulers of China, especially President Jiang Zemin, whose hard-line role in those events has been revived in the official persecution of Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Are The Skeptics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did the deeply ingrained, institutionalized skepticism of our own media crumble so quickly in the face of what smells like a stage-managed incident that&amp;rsquo;s being blatantly exploited for political reasons? Why would so many American news outlets be so gullible? Is it because the whiff of spirituality and mysticism in a culture few of us understand makes some of us uncomfortable in our journalistic practice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my investigation into Falun Gong, I document a disturbing pattern of U.S. media outlets echoing China&amp;rsquo;s charges, including the frequent use of pejorative words like &amp;ldquo;cult&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sect&amp;rdquo; and even &amp;ldquo;mishmash.&amp;rdquo; In some respects the media in our own country also reflect a one-dimensional, stereotyped perspective, downplaying and denigrating a force that doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit into simple left-right political categories and which they may have trouble relating to because of its Asian character and roots in a mix of a Buddhist cultivation practice, Taoism and traditional qigong. Falun Gong is too often treated like the classic &amp;ldquo;other,&amp;rdquo; too weird to be taken seriously or show sympathy toward. (Incidentally, I am not a Falun Gong practitioner, but our company has produced videos for Falun Gong, which gave me access and information I used to write and produce a film and a book on the subject.&amp;ldquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one of my bookstore appearances in Chicago, someone compared Falun Gong and the current situation in China to David Koresh&amp;rsquo;s Branch Davidians and the 51-day siege in 1993 by federal law enforcement officers in Waco, ostensibly to seize guns and protect children from abuse, a comparison China has invoked to make the case that it&amp;rsquo;s only doing what the U.S. government did in combating its own dangerous cult. Someone jumped up to challenge the analogy, arguing that Koresh and company were violent and Falun Gong is not. He was right: There is no direct comparison, except in terms of the response to what happened. Only the hard right-wing in the United States criticized the government&amp;rsquo;s brutal military intervention, which reminded me of the words of that American lieutenant in Vietnam: &amp;ldquo;We destroyed the village in order to save it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of empathy people felt for the families under Koresh&amp;rsquo;s mad control led to many rationalizing or not speaking out against the bloody and illegal suppression that occurred in Waco. Once people are dehumanized in our eyes, we may lose compassion for them and turn the other way when their rights are violated, especially if we dislike their politics and consider them unsympathetic victims. If you want to know the details of where dehumanization leads in China, check out Amnesty International&amp;rsquo;s recent report on the pervasive use of torture, which is often directed at nonviolent Falun Gong practitioners. Beijing, natch, calls that a forgery too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 17, more than a thousand Falun Gong practitioners protested nonviolently in Los Angeles against the persecution going on in China. Few media outlets showed up at their press conference, even though this is a story making headlines worldwide. (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any story about it the next day in The Los Angeles Times, although their book review carried a discussion of what happened in Tiananmen Square in l989.) Media indifference fans public indifference. China&amp;rsquo;s media are doing what you would expect, but how to explain the attitude of the Western media, which has covered the story so episodically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the prominent media play this &amp;ldquo;mass suicide&amp;rdquo; story received, it is not too late to thoroughly investigate not only what happened but whether and why we were all taken in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20021202162929/http://www.mediachannel.org/views/dissector/falungong2.shtml&#34;&gt;Web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>國家評論: 北京在燃燒 - 更多的中國謊言</title>
      <link>/zh/reports/beijing_is_burning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/reports/beijing_is_burning/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;北京在燃燒-更多的中國謊言&#34;&gt;北京在燃燒 - 更多的中國謊言&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;安.努男&lt;/strong&gt;, 勞改研究基金會政策主任&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2001年2月13日&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caught up in its desperate bid to host the 2008 Olympic Games, Beijing is a city in turmoil. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s insistence on soi-disant &amp;ldquo;social and political stability&amp;rdquo; has allowed it to resort to old Communist tactics reminiscent of Chairman Mao. No group knows this better than the Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, on the eve of the Chinese New Year, seven people described as Falun Gong members reportedly tried to commit suicide in Tiananmen Square. Five of the seven succeeded in setting themselves on fire, leaving one woman dead from her injuries and four others severely burned, including the deceased&amp;rsquo;s 12 year-old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was this event staged or allowed to happen by China&amp;rsquo;s government in order to discredit the Falun Gong? It is hardly a far-fetched hypothesis. China&amp;rsquo;s government has promised to extinguish all problems connected with the Falun Gong in advance of the 80th anniversary of Chinese Communism, which Beijing plans on celebrating this July. It has already gone to great lengths to crack down on the banned spiritual movement, accusing it of being a dangerous and wicked cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of Falun Gong practitioners have been hauled off to laogai camps. Still others have been locked up in mental hospitals without the benefit of due process, and at least 140 more have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its intensifying campaign to discredit the sect, China&amp;rsquo;s leaders have now seized on a new target: the Western media. Beijing maintains that several American journalists, including two from CNN, are being investigated on possible murder charges relating to last month&amp;rsquo;s burnings in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report in The Yangcheng Evening News entitled, &amp;ldquo;Witnessing a Mother and Child Self-Immolate and Doing Nothing&amp;ndash;Exactly What Was the Role of Western Journalists?&amp;rdquo; read like a bulletin from Orwell&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Truth. It claimed that &amp;ldquo;unidentified police officials&amp;rdquo; had evidence showing that a few foreign reporters were told in advance that a dramatic Falun Gong event was to take place at the Square on January 23rd. The article said that legal actions would be taken on the murder charge of &amp;ldquo;instigating and abetting a suicide&amp;rdquo; if it could be confirmed the reporters had in fact participated in the planning of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, according to multiple reports, the only foreign reporters who actually witnessed the events included a producer and cameraman for CNN, and both of them say they had received no advance warning of the incident in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, while the Chinese media have been quick to excoriate Western journalists, they have breathlessly exonerated Beijing&amp;rsquo;s police. And yet, the police had clearly been at the ready with fire extinguishers when the self-immolators started the blaze. And in a move unmistakenly designed to rally enmity toward the Falun Gong, PRC officials hastily arranged an interview with the wounded 12 year-old. This poor child, who had suffered large-scale burn injuries, was shepherded into an official interview immediately after undergoing a tracheotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, New York&amp;rsquo;s Falun Dafa Information Center steadfastly rejects reports that the Beijing burn victims were true members of the sect. The deceased woman had never been known to practice Falun Gong exercises; nor had she openly associated herself with the movement. More importantly, the essential teachings of Falun Gong explicitly forbid violence of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also speculation that the burn victims may have sacrificed themselves as a form of desperate protestation against the Communist regime. Justin Yu, a journalist for World Journal, the Chinese-language daily, reflected on the confusion faced by many Chinese over what to believe. &amp;ldquo;The PRC&amp;rsquo;s propaganda coup against the Falun Gong relies upon people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of events in recent Asian history, such as the 73 year-old Buddhist monk in Saigon whose self-immolating is a form of protest to fulfill his beliefs, [like] Koreans cutting off their fingers, and the Japanese ritual of hari-kari. But this situation is not clear. Who do we believe&amp;ndash;the Communists? They have lied to us so many times, another lie for them is nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, one wonders why the Falun Gong would deny its participation if it had organized the burning event as a form of protest? According to the human-rights activist Ann Lau, &amp;ldquo;The PRC is using its same old tactics even though they did not work in the past. For example, China&amp;rsquo;s government insists that there was no famine in the late &amp;lsquo;50s and early &amp;lsquo;60s, yet that famine took 30 million lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been noted that some hard-liners are not even attempting to camouflage their Mao-style tactics. New York Times reporter Erik Eckholm recently quoted (from an article in China&amp;rsquo;s Legal Daily) an old slogan that describes Falun Gong followers as the &amp;ldquo;running dogs of foreign anti-Chinese forces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is wrenching to think that all it took to reinvigorate Beijing&amp;rsquo;s propaganda machine was a few simple breathing exercises. China&amp;rsquo;s war on the Falun Gong revitalizes Mao&amp;rsquo;s dream: to let no aspect of Chinese society escape the party&amp;rsquo;s grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are the 2008 Olympics worth all that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20131029202638/http://old.nationalreview.com/comment/commentprint021301a.html&#34;&gt;Web Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>華盛頓郵報: 人體火焰點燃中國疑團</title>
      <link>/zh/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zh/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;人體火焰點燃中國疑團-公開自焚的動機加劇關於法輪功的爭端-節選-1&#34;&gt;人體火焰點燃中國疑團 - 公開自焚的動機加劇關於法輪功的爭端 (節選&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip_Pan&#34;&gt;菲利普.潘&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2001年2月4日&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KAIFENG, China (Washington Post Foreign Service) — There is a neighborhood on the eastern side of this once-glorious city called Apple Orchard, but there are no apple trees here, only drab concrete buildings and clusters of unemployed men loitering on mud streets. It was here, in a fourth-floor apartment in Building Six, that Liu Chunling and her 12-year-old daughter, Liu Siying, lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mother was a quiet woman who kept to herself, the daughter a lively fifth-grader who never failed to smile and say hello. Neighbors recalled there was something both strange and sad about Liu Chunling, that she sometimes hit her child, that she drove her elderly mother away, that she worked in a nightclub and took money to keep men company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one suspected that Liu, 36, might have joined the banned spiritual movement Falun Gong. And hardly anyone noticed when she and her daughter disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there they were on national television, their bodies engulfed in orange flames in Tiananmen Square. Liu Siying was shown lying on a stretcher, her face and lips charred black, whimpering, “Mama, mama.” Her mother, the newscast reported, was already dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drove the Lius and three others from this city in central Henan province, about 350 miles south of Beijing, to pour gasoline on their bodies and set themselves afire on Jan. 23, the eve of the Chinese New Year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An intense battle is underway to answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ruling Communist Party has launched an all-out campaign to use the incident to turn public opinion in China and abroad against the group it outlawed 18 months ago and has tried to crush, at times with brutal tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning and night, the state-controlled media carry fresh attacks against Falun Gong and its U.S.-based leader, Li Hongzhi. Schools have been ordered to “educate” pupils about the sect. Discussion meetings have been organized in factories, offices and universities. Religious leaders as far away as Tibet have delivered scripted denunciations. In Kaifeng, the post office issued an anti-Falun Gong postmark, and 10,000 people signed a public petition against the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has also used the incident to pressure Hong Kong to ban Falun Gong, testing the strength of the “one country, two systems” setup that gives the former British colony autonomy over its affairs. Falun Gong exists legally in Hong Kong, but the territory’s security chief warned Thursday that police intend to monitor the group’s activities closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong leaders insist that the Lius and their companions could not have been members of their movement, which promotes a mix of Buddhism, Taoism and traditional Chinese breathing exercises. They have said Falun Gong clearly forbids both violence and suicide and have suggested the government may have staged the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other human rights activists say the five set themselves on fire to protest the government’s crackdown on Falun Gong, which has resulted in thousands of arrests and as many as 105 deaths in police custody. All but 12-year-old Liu Siying had protested Beijing’s actions against Falun Gong in Tiananmen Square previously, according to the Hong Kong-based Information Center for Human Rights and Democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a tradition of politically motivated suicide in China. At the start of China’s last dynasty, in the 1640s, hundreds of people killed themselves rather than live under the conquering Manchus. More than 250 years later, several students committed suicide to protest the Qing Dynasty’s refusal to establish a constitutional republic. Most recently, countless Chinese took their lives to escape the abuse of Mao Zedong’s Cultural Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is hardly any precedent for public self-immolation. In Kaifeng, a city of 700,000 that was China’s imperial capital and one of the world’s most populous cities at the turn of the last millennium, most residents took a dim view of what Liu and the others did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They disgraced Kaifeng, and they disgraced China in front of the whole world. It was just too much!” said Tang Shaohua, 60, who runs a grocery around the corner from Liu’s home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so sad what happened to that little girl. I used to see her playing around here,” added neighbor Zhang Binglian, 60. “Falun Gong is an evil cult. I thought that before, and I’m even more convinced now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in Kaifeng, there are signs that the government’s propaganda campaigns have lost some of their effectiveness. Several residents expressed weariness with the barrage against Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not saying I don’t believe the government, but I’m not saying I believe it, either,” said Liu Xiaoyu, 39, as she made dumplings in Kaifeng’s lively night market. “The government controls the news. We all know that now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cab driver Wang Chaohui said he believed Falun Gong was a religion like any other, and said it would be unfair to blame the acts of five individuals on a group with millions of practitioners. In any case, he said, the crackdown on Falun Gong was sure to backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“China is different now, and they can’t arrest everybody who believes in something like this,” he said. “It only makes things worse.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wang said the real question China must confront is why so many people believe in something like Falun Gong. “People are dissatisfied with society,” he said. “That’s the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the rest of China, Kaifeng has experienced a revival in all kinds of religions as communist ideology has lost its appeal. Over the past decade, residents have turned in large numbers to Christianity, Buddhism, Taoism — and Falun Gong. Before the group was banned, hundreds practiced its meditation exercises in the city’s parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong has attracted a cross section of Chinese — party members, senior army officers, bureaucrats, teachers and millions living on the margins of society. In Kaifeng, where several factories have closed and the economy has slumped, many are searching for something to believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state media have said little about why the five who set themselves on fire might have joined Falun Gong. Beijing denied requests to interview Liu Siying and the three other survivors, who are all hospitalized with serious burns. A Kaifeng official said only China Central Television and the official New China News Agency were permitted to speak to their relatives or their colleagues. A man who answered the door at the Liu home referred questions to the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Liu Chunling’s Apple Orchard neighbors described her as a woman who led a troubled life and suffered from psychological problems. State media identified 78-year-old Hao Xiuzhen as her adoptive mother. Neighbors said they quarreled often before Liu drove the woman from their home last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was something wrong with her,” said neighbor Liu Min, 51. “She hit her mother, and her mother was crying and yelling. She hit her daughter, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also questions about how Liu supported herself and about the whereabouts of her daughter’s father. Neighbors said Liu was not a native of Kaifeng, and that a man in southern Guangdong province paid her rent. Others, including neighbor Wen Jian, 22, said Liu worked in a local nightclub and was paid to dine with and dance with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None ever saw her practice Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/?utm_term=.e0b129d43a6c&#34;&gt;Washington Post Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://faluninfo.net/washington-post-human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery-excerpts/&#34;&gt;Falun Info Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The above are excerpts from the original article from The Washington Post, which you can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
