<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title>False Fire Homepage on 偽火</title>
    <link>https://falsefire.com/zh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in False Fire Homepage on 偽火</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://falsefire.com/zh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>關於《偽火》視頻</title>
      <link>https://falsefire.com/zh/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:34:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefire.com/zh/about/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;關於-偽火-視頻&#34;&gt;關於《偽火》視頻&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;分析2001年天安門自焚事件的影片《偽火》（False Fire） 獲获第51屆哥倫布國際電影電視節榮譽獎。該片由北美非盈利中文電視臺“新唐人”製作。頒獎儀式于11月8日在俄亥俄州哥倫布市的隔路藝術設計學院坎薩中心舉行。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在《偽火》這部影片中，新唐人電視臺製作人分析了中國中央電視臺自焚報道的漏洞，揭示天安門自焚事件極有可能是中國江氏政府为栽贓法輪功、並為鎮壓法輪功製造藉口而炮製的一起偽案。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ann Noonan: Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC</title>
      <link>https://falsefire.com/zh/reports/beijing_is_burning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefire.com/zh/reports/beijing_is_burning/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20131029202638/http://old.nationalreview.com/comment/commentprint021301a.html&#34;&gt;Web Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beijing-is-burning-more-lies-from-the-prc&#34;&gt;Beijing is Burning - More Lies from the PRC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong (Excerpts [^1])&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Ann Noonan&lt;/strong&gt;, Policy Director for the Laogai Foundation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 13, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caught up in its desperate bid to host the 2008 Olympic Games, Beijing is a city in turmoil. The PRC&amp;rsquo;s insistence on soi-disant &amp;ldquo;social and political stability&amp;rdquo; has allowed it to resort to old Communist tactics reminiscent of Chairman Mao. No group knows this better than the Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, on the eve of the Chinese New Year, seven people described as Falun Gong members reportedly tried to commit suicide in Tiananmen Square. Five of the seven succeeded in setting themselves on fire, leaving one woman dead from her injuries and four others severely burned, including the deceased&amp;rsquo;s 12 year-old daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was this event staged or allowed to happen by China&amp;rsquo;s government in order to discredit the Falun Gong? It is hardly a far-fetched hypothesis. China&amp;rsquo;s government has promised to extinguish all problems connected with the Falun Gong in advance of the 80th anniversary of Chinese Communism, which Beijing plans on celebrating this July. It has already gone to great lengths to crack down on the banned spiritual movement, accusing it of being a dangerous and wicked cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of Falun Gong practitioners have been hauled off to laogai camps. Still others have been locked up in mental hospitals without the benefit of due process, and at least 140 more have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its intensifying campaign to discredit the sect, China&amp;rsquo;s leaders have now seized on a new target: the Western media. Beijing maintains that several American journalists, including two from CNN, are being investigated on possible murder charges relating to last month&amp;rsquo;s burnings in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report in The Yangcheng Evening News entitled, &amp;ldquo;Witnessing a Mother and Child Self-Immolate and Doing Nothing&amp;ndash;Exactly What Was the Role of Western Journalists?&amp;rdquo; read like a bulletin from Orwell&amp;rsquo;s Ministry of Truth. It claimed that &amp;ldquo;unidentified police officials&amp;rdquo; had evidence showing that a few foreign reporters were told in advance that a dramatic Falun Gong event was to take place at the Square on January 23rd. The article said that legal actions would be taken on the murder charge of &amp;ldquo;instigating and abetting a suicide&amp;rdquo; if it could be confirmed the reporters had in fact participated in the planning of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, according to multiple reports, the only foreign reporters who actually witnessed the events included a producer and cameraman for CNN, and both of them say they had received no advance warning of the incident in Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, while the Chinese media have been quick to excoriate Western journalists, they have breathlessly exonerated Beijing&amp;rsquo;s police. And yet, the police had clearly been at the ready with fire extinguishers when the self-immolators started the blaze. And in a move unmistakenly designed to rally enmity toward the Falun Gong, PRC officials hastily arranged an interview with the wounded 12 year-old. This poor child, who had suffered large-scale burn injuries, was shepherded into an official interview immediately after undergoing a tracheotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, New York&amp;rsquo;s Falun Dafa Information Center steadfastly rejects reports that the Beijing burn victims were true members of the sect. The deceased woman had never been known to practice Falun Gong exercises; nor had she openly associated herself with the movement. More importantly, the essential teachings of Falun Gong explicitly forbid violence of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also speculation that the burn victims may have sacrificed themselves as a form of desperate protestation against the Communist regime. Justin Yu, a journalist for World Journal, the Chinese-language daily, reflected on the confusion faced by many Chinese over what to believe. &amp;ldquo;The PRC&amp;rsquo;s propaganda coup against the Falun Gong relies upon people&amp;rsquo;s understanding of events in recent Asian history, such as the 73 year-old Buddhist monk in Saigon whose self-immolating is a form of protest to fulfill his beliefs, [like] Koreans cutting off their fingers, and the Japanese ritual of hari-kari. But this situation is not clear. Who do we believe&amp;ndash;the Communists? They have lied to us so many times, another lie for them is nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, one wonders why the Falun Gong would deny its participation if it had organized the burning event as a form of protest? According to the human-rights activist Ann Lau, &amp;ldquo;The PRC is using its same old tactics even though they did not work in the past. For example, China&amp;rsquo;s government insists that there was no famine in the late &amp;lsquo;50s and early &amp;lsquo;60s, yet that famine took 30 million lives.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been noted that some hard-liners are not even attempting to camouflage their Mao-style tactics. New York Times reporter Erik Eckholm recently quoted (from an article in China&amp;rsquo;s Legal Daily) an old slogan that describes Falun Gong followers as the &amp;ldquo;running dogs of foreign anti-Chinese forces.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is wrenching to think that all it took to reinvigorate Beijing&amp;rsquo;s propaganda machine was a few simple breathing exercises. China&amp;rsquo;s war on the Falun Gong revitalizes Mao&amp;rsquo;s dream: to let no aspect of Chinese society escape the party&amp;rsquo;s grasp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are the 2008 Olympics worth all that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philip Pan, Washington Post: Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery</title>
      <link>https://falsefire.com/zh/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://falsefire.com/zh/reports/human_fire_ignites_chinese_mystery/</guid>
      
        <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery&#34;&gt;Human Fire Ignites Chinese Mystery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motive for Public Burning Intensifies Fight Over Falun Gong (Excerpts &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;Philip P. Pan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;February 4, 2001&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KAIFENG, China (Washington Post Foreign Service) — There is a neighborhood on the eastern side of this once-glorious city called Apple Orchard, but there are no apple trees here, only drab concrete buildings and clusters of unemployed men loitering on mud streets. It was here, in a fourth-floor apartment in Building Six, that Liu Chunling and her 12-year-old daughter, Liu Siying, lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mother was a quiet woman who kept to herself, the daughter a lively fifth-grader who never failed to smile and say hello. Neighbors recalled there was something both strange and sad about Liu Chunling, that she sometimes hit her child, that she drove her elderly mother away, that she worked in a nightclub and took money to keep men company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one suspected that Liu, 36, might have joined the banned spiritual movement Falun Gong. And hardly anyone noticed when she and her daughter disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, there they were on national television, their bodies engulfed in orange flames in Tiananmen Square. Liu Siying was shown lying on a stretcher, her face and lips charred black, whimpering, “Mama, mama.” Her mother, the newscast reported, was already dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drove the Lius and three others from this city in central Henan province, about 350 miles south of Beijing, to pour gasoline on their bodies and set themselves afire on Jan. 23, the eve of the Chinese New Year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An intense battle is underway to answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ruling Communist Party has launched an all-out campaign to use the incident to turn public opinion in China and abroad against the group it outlawed 18 months ago and has tried to crush, at times with brutal tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning and night, the state-controlled media carry fresh attacks against Falun Gong and its U.S.-based leader, Li Hongzhi. Schools have been ordered to “educate” pupils about the sect. Discussion meetings have been organized in factories, offices and universities. Religious leaders as far away as Tibet have delivered scripted denunciations. In Kaifeng, the post office issued an anti-Falun Gong postmark, and 10,000 people signed a public petition against the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has also used the incident to pressure Hong Kong to ban Falun Gong, testing the strength of the “one country, two systems” setup that gives the former British colony autonomy over its affairs. Falun Gong exists legally in Hong Kong, but the territory’s security chief warned Thursday that police intend to monitor the group’s activities closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong leaders insist that the Lius and their companions could not have been members of their movement, which promotes a mix of Buddhism, Taoism and traditional Chinese breathing exercises. They have said Falun Gong clearly forbids both violence and suicide and have suggested the government may have staged the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other human rights activists say the five set themselves on fire to protest the government’s crackdown on Falun Gong, which has resulted in thousands of arrests and as many as 105 deaths in police custody. All but 12-year-old Liu Siying had protested Beijing’s actions against Falun Gong in Tiananmen Square previously, according to the Hong Kong-based Information Center for Human Rights and Democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a tradition of politically motivated suicide in China. At the start of China’s last dynasty, in the 1640s, hundreds of people killed themselves rather than live under the conquering Manchus. More than 250 years later, several students committed suicide to protest the Qing Dynasty’s refusal to establish a constitutional republic. Most recently, countless Chinese took their lives to escape the abuse of Mao Zedong’s Cultural Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is hardly any precedent for public self-immolation. In Kaifeng, a city of 700,000 that was China’s imperial capital and one of the world’s most populous cities at the turn of the last millennium, most residents took a dim view of what Liu and the others did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They disgraced Kaifeng, and they disgraced China in front of the whole world. It was just too much!” said Tang Shaohua, 60, who runs a grocery around the corner from Liu’s home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s so sad what happened to that little girl. I used to see her playing around here,” added neighbor Zhang Binglian, 60. “Falun Gong is an evil cult. I thought that before, and I’m even more convinced now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even in Kaifeng, there are signs that the government’s propaganda campaigns have lost some of their effectiveness. Several residents expressed weariness with the barrage against Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m not saying I don’t believe the government, but I’m not saying I believe it, either,” said Liu Xiaoyu, 39, as she made dumplings in Kaifeng’s lively night market. “The government controls the news. We all know that now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cab driver Wang Chaohui said he believed Falun Gong was a religion like any other, and said it would be unfair to blame the acts of five individuals on a group with millions of practitioners. In any case, he said, the crackdown on Falun Gong was sure to backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“China is different now, and they can’t arrest everybody who believes in something like this,” he said. “It only makes things worse.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wang said the real question China must confront is why so many people believe in something like Falun Gong. “People are dissatisfied with society,” he said. “That’s the problem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the rest of China, Kaifeng has experienced a revival in all kinds of religions as communist ideology has lost its appeal. Over the past decade, residents have turned in large numbers to Christianity, Buddhism, Taoism — and Falun Gong. Before the group was banned, hundreds practiced its meditation exercises in the city’s parks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falun Gong has attracted a cross section of Chinese — party members, senior army officers, bureaucrats, teachers and millions living on the margins of society. In Kaifeng, where several factories have closed and the economy has slumped, many are searching for something to believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state media have said little about why the five who set themselves on fire might have joined Falun Gong. Beijing denied requests to interview Liu Siying and the three other survivors, who are all hospitalized with serious burns. A Kaifeng official said only China Central Television and the official New China News Agency were permitted to speak to their relatives or their colleagues. A man who answered the door at the Liu home referred questions to the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Liu Chunling’s Apple Orchard neighbors described her as a woman who led a troubled life and suffered from psychological problems. State media identified 78-year-old Hao Xiuzhen as her adoptive mother. Neighbors said they quarreled often before Liu drove the woman from their home last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was something wrong with her,” said neighbor Liu Min, 51. “She hit her mother, and her mother was crying and yelling. She hit her daughter, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also questions about how Liu supported herself and about the whereabouts of her daughter’s father. Neighbors said Liu was not a native of Kaifeng, and that a man in southern Guangdong province paid her rent. Others, including neighbor Wen Jian, 22, said Liu worked in a local nightclub and was paid to dine with and dance with customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None ever saw her practice Falun Gong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/?utm_term=.e0b129d43a6c&#34;&gt;Washington Post Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://faluninfo.net/washington-post-human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery-excerpts/&#34;&gt;Falun Info Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The above are excerpts from the original article from The Washington Post, which you can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/2001/02/04/human-fire-ignites-chinese-mystery/e27303e3-6117-4ec3-b6cf-58f03cdb4773/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
